Guide to the Simon Kornblit Papers, 1950s-2015 and undated RL.11107
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Simon Kornblit Papers, 1950s-2015 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Kornblit, Simon
RL.11107
4.0 Linear Feet
Advertising executive with Doyle Dane Bernbach and DDB Needham agencies in the New York and Los Angeles offices; marketing executive for Universal Pictures.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically.
Biographical / Historical
1933 Aug. 1--Born Antwerp, Belgium; 1951--Mailroom employee, Doyle Dane Bernbach (DDB), N.Y.; 1960--Account executive, DDB NY; 1966--Vice President, DDB NY; 1974--Senior Vice President, DDB NY; 1982--Director of Client Services, DDB; 1986--General Manager, DDB/West, Los Angeles; 1987-1993--Head, Worldwide Marketing, Universal Pictures; 1994--Board member, Atlanta Film Festival and Atlanta Jewish Film Festival; 1996--Olympics Community Hero Torchbearer; 2000-2002 Director, Film Institute, Kennesaw State University Continuing Education
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
In addition, original audiovisual materials are closed to research until use copies can be produced.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Simon Kornblit Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2015.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
Lore Parker Papers; Jacqueline End Papers; Thomas Garbett Papers
Collection Overview
Collection spans the 1950s-2015 and includes policy and training manuals, speeches and writings and press clippings, other printed materials, print advertisements, photographs, slides, and other materials that relate to Kornblit's career in advertising at the Doyle Dane Bernbach (DDB) and DDB Needham agencies. Companies referenced include American Tourister (American Luggage), Thom McCan shoes, and Volkswagen. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Advertising executives; Advertising -- United States -- History; Advertising agencies -- United States -- Management; Kornblit, Simon
- Simon Kornblit Papers, 1950s-2015 and undated; 1
  - Biographical, 2010-2015 and undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Biographical--article in The Archway, 1972 Nov. 17 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Biographical--Institute of Advanced Studies certificate, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Biographical--Kornblit career press and memoranda, 1973-1987 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Biographical--Simon Kornblilt the DDB Years 1951-1987, 2015 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - DDB (Doyle Dane Bernbach)--Account Management Manual, undated (Box 6)
  - DDB--Annual reports, 1965-1985; 2 folders (Box 1, Folder 4-5)
  - DDB--Bill Bernbach retrospective, Back Stage, 1982 July 16 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - DDB--Bill Bernbach Said, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - DDB--Bill Bernbach speeches and articles, 1960-1982 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - DDB--Clients--American Tourister, 1970-1978 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - DDB-Clients--Thom McCan radio spots (It was a very good year, Can't buy me love, I should have known better) 1/4 audio tape, 1968 Dec. 20 (Box 4)
  - DDB--Clients--Volkswagen, 1960-1968 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - DDB--Farewell gift to Kornblit (compilation of press clippings), 1987 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - DDB--ROI (Relevance, Originality, Impact) program, including presentation to Universal Pictures, 1986-1987; 3 folders (Box 2, Folder 1-3)
  - DDB Needham--Credentials book, circa 1987 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - DDB Needham--ROI Guidebook, 1991 (Box 7)
  - DDB Needham--Speaking with One Voice, circa 1989 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - DDB News, 1979 June (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Effective Presentation Skills course workbook, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Photograph album--DDB photos of Simon "Si" Kornblit, undated (Box 5)
  - Photograph albums, 1969-circa 1981 and undated; 4 folders (Box 2, Folder 8-11)
  - Photographs, circa 1980s and undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Photographs--Coed softball DDB/West Los Angeles vs. Della Femina, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Photographs--DDb photos of Simon Kornblit (binder), 1950s-1979 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Photographs--DDB/LA holiday party, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Photographs--DDB/LA holiday party negatives, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Saturday Evening Post--Inside Madison Avenue (Martin Mayer), 1965 Mar. 13 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Simon "Si" Kornblit: The DDB Years 1951-1987, excerpts of collection on CD-R, 2015 (Box 4)
  - Slides--American Tourister, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Slides--DDB/LA, 1978 and undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Speech--Telling Isn't Selling (Allen G. Rosenshine, BBDO), 1980 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Speech file--Account management, undated (Box 3, Folder 8-9)
  - Speech file--Account management (Wade Davis original drawings), undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Speeches and reprints by others, 1975-1987 and undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Speeches and reprints by others, 1975-1987 and undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Speeches by Kornblit, 1973-1980s (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - WSAAA (Western States Advertising Agencies Association)--McKinney Committee, 1996-1997 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Youth Opportunity Council (Hubert Humphrey), circa 1967 (Box 4, Folder 4)